<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Mohammad Faseeh Ahmed</title>
    <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Mohammad Faseeh Ahmed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis on Various Commodities </title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/commodity-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/commodity-management/</guid>
      <description>Project overview In this project I learned about the time series analysis using Deep Learning and also learned how to built a scraper which can scrape data, based on respective timeline provided and can give output in csv or an excel file. improved my visualization skills using seaborn and matplotlib.
Analytical Insights From Last 5 Years
● Crude Oil prices is strongly correlated with Brent Oil and Natural Gas
● Crude Oil prices is positively correlated with Copper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web based Mitosis detection on Breast Cancer whole slide images using FasterRCNN and YOLOv5 </title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/publications/mitosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/publications/mitosis/</guid>
      <description>Publication overview This paper was published by Science and Information Organization in International Journal of Advanced Computer Science Applications(IJACA), &amp;ldquo;Web based Mitosis detection on Breast Cancer whole slide images using FasterRCNN and YOLOv5&amp;rdquo;, It uses Mitosis which is one of the critical biomarker in Nottingham Breast Cancer Grading.
Tech Stack ● Image Preprocessing - QuPath, Groovy
● Frontend - HistomicsUI(CADD4MBC)
● Database - MongoDB
● Deep learning Inference- YOLOv5, FasterRCNN</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tubules Detection on Breast Carcinoma Whole Slide Images using Artificial Intelligence Deep Learning Model</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/publications/tubules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/publications/tubules/</guid>
      <description>Publication overview We are presenting at John Hopkins Hospital, Baltimore, MD, USA at SIMMI-CMIMI22, International Conference On Machine Intelligence an Medical Imaging, &amp;ldquo;Tubules Detection on Breast Carcinoma Whole Slide Images using Artificial Intelligence Deep Learning Model&amp;rdquo;, An one of the critical biomarker in Nottingham Breast Cancer Grading.
Tech Stack ● Image Preprocessing - QuPath, Groovy
● Frontend - HistomicsUI(CADD4MBC)
● Database - MongoDB
● Deep learning Inference- R2U-Net
● Deep learning training - Tensorflow, R2U-Net</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beverage Management System</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/beverage-management-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/beverage-management-system/</guid>
      <description>Project overview This Web App aids in mobile inventory management. The frontend of the mobile device shows a stream of things being displayed; a deep learning model uses this data to identify the objects and automatically updates the Inventory Database frontend display with the changes.
● Using state of the art Yolov5 model with detection speed as low as 5ms per frame.
● Built the frontend using Streamlit.
● Using SQLite3 as a Database for managing inventory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Kidney Disease Predictor</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/kidney-disease-predictor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/kidney-disease-predictor/</guid>
      <description>Project overview Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is a global health problem with high morbidity and mortality rate, and it induces other diseases. Since there are no obvious values during the early stages of CKD, patients often fail to notice the disease. Early detection of CKD enables patients to receive timely treatment to ameliorate the progression of this disease. Machine learning models can effectively aid clinicians achieve this goal due to their fast and accurate recognition performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid19 Bot</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/covid19-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/covid19-bot/</guid>
      <description>Project overview Chatbot is a computer program designed to simulate conversation with human users, especially over the internet. Simple chatbots work based on pre-written keywords that they understand, each of these commands must be written by the developer separately using regular expressions or other form of string analysis, if the user has asked a question without using a single keyword the bot cannot understand it and as a rule responds with default messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Price Predictor</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/car-price-predictor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/projects/car-price-predictor/</guid>
      <description>Project overview
Car Price Prediction using Machine Learning is found to be really helpful in predicting prices of used vehicles, with increase in demand for used cars more and vehicle buyers are finding alternatives of buying new cars. There is a need of accurate price prediction mechanism for the used cars. Prediction techniques of machine learning can be helpful in this regard.
Tech Stack Front end: HTML, CSS, BootStrap Backend: Flask, Nodejs Languages: Python, Javascript Model : Random Forest Regression Ide: VS code Other libraries : Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Sklearn Data set : https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>Resume
I am a Machine Learning Engineer with an extensive background in Full Stack Development and Computer Vision.
I have worked on various End to End Projects projects, Recently I have built many projects such as a Chronic Kidney Disease Predictor which is a web application built using MERN Stack that uses Machine Learning to predict whether a person has a chronic kidney disease or not. I have also built a Beverage Management System built using Streamlit, Python and YOLOv5 that helps in managing inventory in real-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms
Platforms Github Linkedin Medium Twitter Kaggle </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
