<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Faseeh Ahmed</title>
    <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Faseeh Ahmed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis on Various Commodities </title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/commodity-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/commodity-management/</guid>
      <description>Project overview In this project learned about time series analysis using deep learning =, also learned how to built a scraper which can scrape data based on respective timeline provided and can give output in csv or excel file. improved my visualization skills using seaborn
Analytic Insights From Last 5 Years
● Crude Oil prices is strongly correlated with Brent Oil and Natural Gas
● Crude Oil prices is positively correlated with Copper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beverage Management System</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/beverage-management-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/beverage-management-system/</guid>
      <description>Project overview This web application aids in mobile inventory system management. The frontend of the mobile device shows a stream of things being displayed; a deep learning model uses this data to identify the objects and automatically update the inventory list&amp;rsquo;s frontend display with the most recent inventory count.
● Using state of the art Yolov5 model with detection speed as low as 5ms per frame.
● Built the frontend using Streamlit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Kidney Disease Predictor</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/kidney-disease-predictor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/kidney-disease-predictor/</guid>
      <description>Project overview Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is a global health problem with high morbidity and mortality rate, and it induces other diseases. Since there are no obvious values during the early stages of CKD, patients often fail to notice the disease. Early detection of CKD enables patients to receive timely treatment to ameliorate the progression of this disease. Machine learning models can effectively aid clinicians achieve this goal due to their fast and accurate recognition performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid19 Bot</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/covid19-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/covid19-bot/</guid>
      <description>Project overview Chatbot is a computer program designed to simulate conversation with human users, especially over the internet. Simple chatbots work based on pre-written keywords that they understand, each of these commands must be written by the developer separately using regular expressions or other form of string analysis, if the user has asked a question without using a single keyword the bot cannot understand it and as a rule responds with default messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Price Predictor</title>
      <link>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/car-price-predictor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faseehahmed26.github.io/portfolio/post/car-price-predictor/</guid>
      <description>Project overview
Car Price Prediction using Machine Learning is especially helpful when the vehicle is used and not coming direct from the factory. With increase in demand for used cars more and more vehicle buyers are finding alternatives of buying new cars. There is a need of accurate price prediction mechanism for the used cars. Prediction techniques of machine learning can be helpful in this regard.
Tech Stack Front end: HTML, CSS, BootStrap Backend: Flask, Nodejs Languages: Python, Javascript Model : Random Forest Regression Ide: VS code Other libraries : Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Sklearn Data set : https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
